<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lane, Richard R. | Xinlun Cheng</title>
    <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/lane-richard-r./</link>
      <atom:link href="https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/lane-richard-r./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lane, Richard R.</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://chengxinlun.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Lane, Richard R.</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/lane-richard-r./</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemo-dynamical tagging in the outskirts: The origins of stellar substructures in the Magellanic Clouds</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2023_aa_680_a79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2023_aa_680_a79/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present the first detailed chemical analysis from APOGEE-2S observations of stars in six regions of recently discovered substructures in the outskirts of the Magellanic Clouds  extending to 20$^{\circ}$ from the LMC center. We also present, for the first time, the metallicity and $\alpha$-abundance radial gradients of the LMC and SMC out to 11$^{\circ}$ and 6$^{\circ}$, respectively. Our chemical tagging includes 13 species including light, $\alpha$, and Fe-peak elements. We find that the abundances of all of these chemical elements in stars populating two regions in the northern periphery &amp;mdash; along the northern &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo;-like feature &amp;mdash; show good agreement with the chemical patterns of the LMC, and thus likely have an LMC origin. For substructures located in the southern periphery of the LMC, we find more complex chemical and kinematical signatures, indicative of a mix of LMC-like and SMC-like populations. However, the shouthern region closest to the LMC shows better agreement with the LMC whereas that closest to the SMC shows a much better agreement with the SMC chemical pattern. When combining this information with 3-D kinematical information for these stars, we conclude that the southern region closest to the LMC has likely an LMC origin whereas that closest to the SMC has an SMC origin and the other two southern regions have a mix of LMC and SMC origins. Our results add to the evidence that the southern substructures of the LMC periphery are the product of close interactions between the LMC and SMC, and thus likely hold important clues that can constrain models of their detailed dynamical histories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Kinematical Analysis of Substructure in the Southern Periphery of the Large Magellanic Cloud </title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2022apj...928...95c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2022apj...928...95c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We report the first 3-D kinematical measurements of 88 stars in the direction of several recently discovered substructures in the southern periphery of the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) using a combination of &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; proper motions and radial velocities from the APOGEE-2 survey. More specifically, we explore stars lie in assorted APOGEE-2 pointings in a region of the LMC periphery where various overdensities of stars have previously been identified in maps of stars from &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; and DECam. By using a model of the LMC disk rotation, we find that a sizeable fraction of the APOGEE-2 stars have extreme space velocities that are distinct from, and not a simple extension of, the LMC disk. Using N-body hydrodynamical simulations of the past dynamical evolution and interaction of the LMC and Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC), we explore whether the extreme velocity stars may be accounted for as tidal debris created in the course of that interaction. We conclude that the combination of LMC and SMC debris produced from their interaction is a promising explanation, although we cannot rule out other possible origins, and that these new data should be used to constrain future simulations of the LMC-SMC interaction. We also conclude that many of the stars in the southern periphery of the LMC lie out of the LMC plane by several kpc. Given that the metallicity of these stars suggest they are likely of Magellanic origin, our results suggest that a wider exploration of the past interaction history of the Magellanic Clouds is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Exploring the Galactic Warp through Asymmetries in the Kinematics of the Galactic Disk</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020apj...905...49c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020apj...905...49c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous analyses of large databases of Milky Way stars have revealed the stellar disk of our Galaxy to be warped and that this imparts a strong signature on the kinematics of stars beyond the solar neighborhood. However, due to the limitation of accurate distance estimates, many attempts to explore the extent of these Galactic features have generally been restricted to a volume near the Sun. By combining Gaia DR2 astrometric solution, StarHorse distance and stellar abundances from the APOGEE survey, we present the most detailed and radially expansive study yet of the vertical and radial motions of stars in the Galactic disk. We map stellar velocity with respect to their Galactocentric radius, angular momentum, and azimuthal angle and assess their relation to the warp. A decrease in vertical velocity is discovered at Galactocentric radius $R=13$ kpc and angular momentum $L_z=2800$ kpc km s$^{-1}$. Smaller ripples in vertical and radial velocity are also discovered superposed on the main trend. We also discovered that trends in the vertical velocity with azimuthal angle are not symmetric about the peak, suggesting the warp to be lopsided. To explain the global trend in vertical velocity, we built a simple analytical model of the Galactic warp. Our best fit yields a starting radius of $8.87^{+0.08}_{-0.09}$ kpc and precession rate of $13.57^{+0.20}_{-0.18}$ km s$^{-1}$ kpc$^{-1}$. These parameters remain consistent across stellar age groups, a result that supports the notion that the warp is the result of an external, gravitationally induced phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
