<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beers, Timothy C. | Xinlun Cheng</title>
    <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/beers-timothy-c./</link>
      <atom:link href="https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/beers-timothy-c./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Beers, Timothy C.</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://chengxinlun.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Beers, Timothy C.</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/beers-timothy-c./</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stellar Velocity Distribution Function in the Milky Way Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020aj....160...43a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020aj....160...43a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stellar velocity distribution function (DF) in the solar vicinity is re-examined using data from the SDSS APOGEE survey&amp;rsquo;s DR16 and &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; DR2. By exploiting APOGEE&amp;rsquo;s ability to chemically discriminate with great reliability the thin disk, thick disk and (accreted) halo populations, we can, for the first time, derive the three-dimensional velocity DFs for these chemically-separated populations. We employ this smaller, but more data-rich APOGEE+&lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; sample to build a &lt;em&gt;data-driven model&lt;/em&gt; of the local stellar population velocity DFs, and use these as basis vectors for assessing the relative density proportions of these populations over 5 &amp;lt; R &amp;lt; 12 kpc, and -1.5 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.5 kpc range as derived from the larger, more complete (i.e., all-sky, magnitude-limited) &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; database. We find that $81.9 \pm 3.1$% of the objects in the selected &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; data-set are thin-disk stars, $16.6 \pm 3.2$% are thick-disk stars, and $1.5 \pm 0.1$% belong to the Milky Way stellar halo. We also find the local thick-to-thin-disk density normalization to be $\rho_{T}(R_{\odot})/\rho_{t}(R_{\odot}) = 2.1 \pm 0.2$%, a result consistent with, but determined in a completely different way than, typical starcount/density analyses. Using the same methodology, the local halo-to-disk density normalization is found to be $\rho_{H}(R_{\odot})/(\rho_{T}(R_{\odot}) + \rho_{t}(R_{\odot})) = 1.2 \pm 0.6$%, a value that may be inflated due to chemical overlap of halo and metal-weak thick disk stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
