<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arras, Phil | Xinlun Cheng</title>
    <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/arras-phil/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/arras-phil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Arras, Phil</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://chengxinlun.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Arras, Phil</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/authors/arras-phil/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The surface mass density of the Milky Way: does the traditional $K_Z$ approach work in the context of new surveys?</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2024_mnras_527_959/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2024_mnras_527_959/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We revisit the classical $K_Z$ problem &amp;mdash; determination of the vertical force and implied total mass density distribution of the Milky Way disk &amp;mdash; for a wide range of Galactocentric radius and vertical height using chemically selected thin and thick disk samples based on APOGEE spectroscopy combined with the &lt;em&gt;Gaia&lt;/em&gt; astrometry. We derived the velocity dispersion profiles in Galactic cylindrical coordinates, and solved the Jeans Equation for the two samples separately. The result is surprising that the total surface mass density as a function of vertical height as derived for these two chemically distinguished populations are different. The discrepancies are larger in the inner compared to the outer Galaxy, with the density calculated from thick disk being larger, independent of the Galactic radius. Furthermore, while there is an overall good agreement between the total mass density derived for the thick disk population and the Standard Halo Model for vertical heights larger than 1 kpc, close to the midplane the mass density observed using the thick disk population is larger than the predicted from the Standard Halo Model. We explore various implications of these discrepancies, and speculate their sources, including problems associated with the assumed density laws, velocity dispersion profiles, and  the Galactic rotation curve, potential non-equilibrium of the Galactic disk, or a failure of the NFW dark matter halo profile for the Milky Way. We conclude that the growing detail in hand on the chemodynamical distributions of Milky Way stars challenges traditional analytical treatments of the $K_Z$ problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galactic Warp Through the Lenses of Gaia Data Release 2 and the APOGEE Survey</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/jan2021_aas237/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/jan2021_aas237/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRESS RELEASE: Galactic Warp Through the Lenses of Gaia Data Release 2 and the APOGEE Survey</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/jan2021_aas237_press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/jan2021_aas237_press/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 3D visualization of the warp of the Milky Way galaxy has been made for the press release. Click on the &lt;code&gt;project&lt;/code&gt; button next to the &lt;code&gt;PDF&lt;/code&gt; button to go to the animations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the press conference on Jan 15 2021, the story has been picked up by many media outlets across the globe, including but not limited to&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Exploring the Galactic Warp through Asymmetries in the Kinematics of the Galactic Disk</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020apj...905...49c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/publication/2020apj...905...49c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous analyses of large databases of Milky Way stars have revealed the stellar disk of our Galaxy to be warped and that this imparts a strong signature on the kinematics of stars beyond the solar neighborhood. However, due to the limitation of accurate distance estimates, many attempts to explore the extent of these Galactic features have generally been restricted to a volume near the Sun. By combining Gaia DR2 astrometric solution, StarHorse distance and stellar abundances from the APOGEE survey, we present the most detailed and radially expansive study yet of the vertical and radial motions of stars in the Galactic disk. We map stellar velocity with respect to their Galactocentric radius, angular momentum, and azimuthal angle and assess their relation to the warp. A decrease in vertical velocity is discovered at Galactocentric radius $R=13$ kpc and angular momentum $L_z=2800$ kpc km s$^{-1}$. Smaller ripples in vertical and radial velocity are also discovered superposed on the main trend. We also discovered that trends in the vertical velocity with azimuthal angle are not symmetric about the peak, suggesting the warp to be lopsided. To explain the global trend in vertical velocity, we built a simple analytical model of the Galactic warp. Our best fit yields a starting radius of $8.87^{+0.08}_{-0.09}$ kpc and precession rate of $13.57^{+0.20}_{-0.18}$ km s$^{-1}$ kpc$^{-1}$. These parameters remain consistent across stellar age groups, a result that supports the notion that the warp is the result of an external, gravitationally induced phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Galactic Warp Through Asymmetries in the Kinematics of the Galactic Disk</title>
      <link>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/oct2020_ias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chengxinlun.github.io/talk/oct2020_ias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
